Alexandre Cela

London I +447463376967 I alexandrecelap@gmail.com I Website I LinkedIn I GitHub

Summary

Highly accomplished Senior Analytics Engineer, with a speciality in Financial Engineering. I have over 6 years of track record in building end-to-end data solutions that directly impact revenue and operational efficiency. I have become a go to person when it comes to building clarity and simple data models from all kinds of messy sources, with all kinds of relevant tooling (web scraping, dbt, python). Crucially, I have proven my ability able synergise with teammates from various seniority levels and backgrounds in order to build great outcomes

Professional Experience

Senior Data Scientist Pregin & Blackrock | London | Aug 2023 - Present

- Led the development of a client-facing BI product for private capital benchmarks, which generated over £2mn in new revenue by structuring messy, raw data into a reliable source for analytics. Played a critical role in the product successfully going native, thanks to expertise and great team collaboration
- Hands-on building of curated and robust private credit data models from multiple messy (and unexplored) sources and web scraping, which will be the foundation for future lucrative Index and ETF products.
- Spearheaded the development of our gold-standard user interaction data model, with dbt and CI/CD. 10x the ability to understand user behaviour, and understand how to increase user LTV
- Championed a data-driven culture by building analytics self service foundation, and training product managers on how to self serve. Reproducible analysis with streamlit and dataset agnostic python code
- Identified ROI opportunities through product usage analysis, leading to a new user onboarding survey that boosted new user activation by 35%.
- Management experience: mentoring a junior analyst to 3x team leverage and output

Senior Product Scientist, Indeed Flex | London | May 2021 - Jun 2023

- Owned and revamped a core pay rate uplift logic, reducing costs by 50% while preserving revenue, by connecting analytics with business outcomes.
- Designed, created, and deployed complex data models using dbt and CI/CD, which enabled robust tracking, self-serve analytics, and streamlined experimentation.

Technical Lead, Voc Al (Startup Project) | London | Jun 2023 – Aug 2023

• Led the technical development of a SaaS product using NLP and Generative AI, gaining hands-on experience with go-to-market strategy and lean engineering team management.

Data Analyst, Nike | Europe HQ | Aug 2019 - Aug 2020

• Automated reporting processes, significantly reducing manual reporting time and improving delivery tracking and success for high-stakes product launches.

Skills & Tools

- Data Modeling & Warehousing: dbt, Snowflake, Snowpark, BigQuery, Redshift, PostgreSQL
- **Programming:** SQL (Advanced), Python (Advanced), Git, Github, Docker, Web Scraping, JavaScript (beginner), Vibecoding (Windsurf, advanced)
- Visualization: , Streamlit, Power BI, Tableau, Metabase, Redash
- ETL/ELT: Apache Spark, AWS, GCP
- Other: Generative AI with LLMs, Machine Learning, Data Quality, CI/CD

Education

- Essec Business School, Paris I Sept 2015 Jun 2019
 - Major in Business Analytics & Data Science, Applied Mathematics, and Financial Markets
- Stanford University, Online Certificates
 - Machine Learning (Andrew Ng), Deep Learning, Generative AI with LLMs,
 Fundamentals of Data Engineering, Data Engineering Zoomcamp